### Luca Francesca

Tel: +353 874655329

E-mail: luca@lucafrancesca.me

Current Occupation: DevOps Engineer

#### Who am I:

I'm a Unix and GNU/Linux based DevOps Engineer (with DNS,Web and Mail Server dealings) who works well in a team but, if the situation demands it, can hold my own in solo projects. Having worked on QA, Production and Mission Critical environment, I'm very flexible. I also like scripting (Bash, Python, Perl, Groovy) on Linux based as well as Windows based infrastructure to achieve a better integration into information systems.

Had my battles with Mysql and Oracle, as well as with some skirmishes with SQL Server. I don't dislike a little tuning when the situation arises.

Believer of the OpenSource methodology, I work just as well with proprietary one, selecting the best piece of software/hardware for the task at hand.

What I don't lack is the curiosity to learn and to better myself and the place where I work.

Open to learn from the people around me as well as share my knowledge.

All that with the goal to reach the target in a fast, cost-effective, precise and complete manner. Virtualisation (VMware and Xen with some gigs with KVM) is also something I like very much alongside Infosec, another passion of mine.

### History

• From June 2015 to Today

DevOps Engineer at Xanadu, Ireland.

Automation of provisioning of environments and applications (environments pipelines) with the use of Jenkins, Fabric and SaltStack.

Management of Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS) on a VMware based infrastructure.

Support of different teams with CI/CD issues.

I'm part of the team tasked with automation of all the software we own.

With a project started 1 year ago and now ended, I created a system that using Jenkins and custom bash and python scripts, checks when a commit is made on any of our repo and it automatically builds the related component.

Afterwards it deploys the software in different environments and does testing before progressing. When the process is done, the component it's released in production.

All of this without manual intervention.

Platform of choice for all of this was Jenkins which I introduced in the company.

Orchestrator tool is SaltStack, used because Python is the second language in the company and one of my favourites.

All the while, I'm also consulting with Infra team on how to provision environments and on my way

to automate that.

My side projects include: support to Dev teams, improvements of best practices, managing issues on non prod environment.

• From *April 2014* to *May 2015* 

Enterprise Services Engineer at BetVictor, Leanse Place, 50 Town Range, Gibraltar Support for middleware and to the VMware team as a part of the Infrastructure. Management of ActiveMQ, Redis and custom tools writing with Groovy, Python and Bash.

Was part of the team that was in charge of day-to-day performance of the platform of the company.

That included tuning and tweaking software and hardware to have them meet SLAs. Custom scripting was used to automate any and all the repetitive and problematic tasks.

• From November 2013 to April 2014

ICT Consultant at Aubay Italia S.p.A, Largo la Foppa 2, 20121 Milan, Italy. Working on client site

(February 2014 – April 2014) *Vodafone Italy Production:* Microsoft SQL Server Administrator working on Vodafone Italy Production systems and supporting Prod environment.

(November 2013 – February 2014) *Matrix S.p.a.*: System Administrator working with networking (Apache, Nginx, DNS), monitoring (Nagios), configuration (Puppet) and scripting (Perl,Python,Bash)

• From June 2013 to October 2013

Junior System Administrator at ePress Information Services Srl, Via Legioni Romane 43,20147 Milan, Italy

Online Technical Support to EidosMedia Methode worldwide customers (News and Media organisations in Europe, US, India and Australia) on mission critical production environment. Clients included The Washington Post,DowJones,The New York Post,Media News Group,Fairfax Business Media,News Corporation,WAZ Mediengruppe,Medienholding Süd GmbH,Crédit Mutuel,Groupe Centre France,Groupe Figaro,Media24,Seattle Times,EuroInformation, and Financial Times.

Use of Veritas Cluster, NetApp appliance, Versant Object DB, Red Hat servers, Python scripting

• From November 2012 to June 2013

Integration Consulting for Integration Testing/Validation Department of Vodafone Italy NTT Data Italy(Viale Cassala 14/b, Milan, Italy) working for Sogetel Srl, Via Giunio Antonio Resti, 63, 00143, Rome, Italy

ICT Consultant, assigned to Vodafone Integration Testing/Validation department (QA

environment) working with Oracle DB and Win32/64 and \*NIX servers and clients.

• From January 2010 to Today

Independent and on-demand scripting for small projects on local and abroad clients. Use of Java, Mysql, Oracle and Sqlite with Python and Perl.

• From October 2011 to October 2012

Volunteer for the National Civil Service, at UILDM Pavia, Italy working with people affected with muscular dystrophy

#### Education

- University of Padova, 2016-2019
  Student in the graduate program in Mathematics
- University of Pavia, 2007 2011. Student in the graduate program in Mathematics
- Humanistic Studies, 2002 2007 at Liceo Classico Benedetto Cairoli, 27029, Vigevano (PV), Italy.

#### **Skills**

- - GNU/Linux (Debian 15 years, Slackware, Arch Linux, OpenSuse, Oracle Enterprise Linux, CentOS, Red Hat Enterprise Linux)
  - Unix (FreeBSD, OpenBSD)
  - Windows (Client, 3.1 → Windows 10; Server, 2008 R2)
- Networking: knowledge of Cisco ASA and management of Cisco router and switch.
   Management of small/medium network
   ISO/OSI protocols knowledge.
   Use of Veritas Clustering.
  - Tuning of Nagios monitoring system.
- Database: MySql, Oracle, SQLite, Versant
- Storage: NetApp
- Programming language C, Sed/Awk, Java, Regex, PL/SQL.
- Scripting language: Bash, Python, Perl
- Git

# Certifications

- VMware Certified Associate Cloud License 14462567-A065-6408FFDE1AB6
- First Certificate in English, University of Cambridge, License 063IT32210054.

# Language skills

• Italian (native), English, Spanish